<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="nice_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>Terms of Use</p>
    <p>Med+Pass End User License Agreement (EULA)</p>
    <p>IMPORTANT: PLEASE READ THIS AGREEMENT CAREFULLY.</p>
    <p>Welcome to Med+Pass’s Site. Med+Pass is a developer and distributor of educational and medical record management hardware, software, and mobile applications. Med+Pass also provides Services to Educational Institutions, which use its proprietary Program.</p>
    <p>This Agreement is between Med+Pass and User. Please read this Agreement carefully, as User accepts and agrees to be bound by all Terms by accessing and/or using the Site, Program and/or Services. If User does not accept or agree to be bound by the Terms of this Agreement, then User should not access or use the Site, Program and/or Services, and User must immediately exit this Site and/or discontinue use of the Program and/or Services. The access and/or use of the Site, Program and/or Services signifies User’s acceptance and continued acceptance of the Terms, this Agreement and any revisions to them.</p>
    <p>The Site, Program, and/or Services are accessible and usable only by Users (and/or their Representatives) who consent to and authorize any and all privacy waivers requested by Med+Pass and who are eighteen (18) years of age or older. By accessing and/or using the Site, Program and/or Services, the User acknowledges, represents and warrants that User will consent to and authorize any and all privacy waivers requested by Med+Pass and that User meets all eligibility requirements.</p>
    <p>In addition to the terms of this Agreement, an Educational Institution and/or Healthcare Provider shall be bound by (i) the terms and conditions of any other agreement applicable to access and use of the Program and/or Services, including any applicable TSA, and (ii) the terms and conditions of use for any other Med+Pass product and/or service. If there is any conflict between the terms of another agreement and this Agreement, then this Agreement shall govern and control in all respects.</p>
        <p><b>1. Definitions.</b></p>
        <p>All capitalized terms used in this Agreement shall have the meanings ascribed below and/or elsewhere in this Agreement:</p>
<p>a. <b>Agreement:</b> this “End User License Agreement / Terms of Use,” including all its Terms as amended and/or modified by Med+Pass from time to time, which is accessible through the Site (www.medpasshealth.com/Policies/EULA) and/or an Application;</p>
<p>b. <b>Account:</b> a Student’s personal portal, accessible by the Site and/or an Application, to which the Student has secure access, through which the Student may engage in the uses identified in subparagraph 3.b. below;</p>
<p>c. <b>Application:</b> any and all hardware, software, and/or mobile applications developed in conjunction with the Program designed to assist Persons (including Educational Institutions) in obtaining, verifying, storing, providing, managing, updating and/or distributing educational and/or medical records such as immunization records;</p>
<p>d. <b>Healthcare Provider:</b> a Person (including an Educational Institution) who provides medical, mental and/or other health care services to another Person and/or submits or causes the submission of records and/or information about a Person’s medical, mental and/or health care treatment, including, for example, “individually identifiable health information,” “protected health information,” “protected information,” “personally identifiable information” and/or “educational information” as those phrases may be defined by applicable law and regulations, including the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act and the Health Insurance Portability and Accessibility Act of 1996, as amended;</p>
<p>e. <b>Educational Institution:</b> a Person who provides instructional services to other Persons, including public and/or private institutions of learning such as K through 12 schools, vocational / technical schools, post-secondary institutions and other institutions of learning.</p>
<p>f. <b>Med+Pass:</b> MedPass Health LLC.</p>
<p>g. <b>Person:</b> any and all natural person(s), governmental entity(ies) (and agency(ies) or department(s) thereof), quasi-public entity(ies), corporation(s), partnership(s), venture(s), trust(s), and all other forms of organization, association or business entity;</p>
<p>h. <b>Program:</b> the proprietary platform developed by Med+Pass and/or its Representatives to facilitate the submission, transfer, uploading, collection, verification, management, maintenance, updating, distribution, and storage of documents and/or information (such as educational and/or medical records), including, but not limited to, any and all aspects of the Program, Application, Services and Site, along with any part or subpart and division or subdivision thereto;</p>
<p>i. <b>Representative(s):</b> any and all officer(s), director(s), shareholder(s), member(s), manager(s), partner(s), principal(s), proprietor(s), venturer(s), employee(s), independent contractor(s), consultant(s), agent(s), attorney(s), parent(s), parent(s), subsidiary(ies), affiliate(s), division(s), predecessor(s)- or successor(s)-in-interest, guarantor(s), permitted assign(s), heir(s) and/or any Person acting for, in concert and/or on behalf of another Persons.</p>
<p>j. <b>Service(s):</b> any and all services provided by Med+Pass and/or its proprietary Program, including, but not limited to, the services concerning, relating to or involving educational and/or medical records and/or an Educational Institution’s compliance with and/or enforcement of immunization requirements;</p>
<p>k. <b>Site:</b> Med+Pass’s website (www.medpasshealth.com), including, but not limited to, any pages or subpages and sections or subsections thereof, and any links to the Program accessible through the Site;</p>
<p>l. <b>Student:</b> any individual enrolled at an Educational Institution who must submit educational and/or medical records through the Program;</p>
<p>m. <b>Term(s):</b> any and all terms and conditions set forth in (i) this Agreement; (ii) any other document expressly incorporated by reference in this Agreement; and (iii) any document expressly incorporating this Agreement;</p>
<p>n. <b>TSA:</b> the contract entered into between Med+Pass and an Educational Institution, which may set forth specific details or custom specifications of the Program as it is to be implemented at the Educational Institution and used by its Students and/or a Student’s or Educational Institution’s Healthcare Provider;</p>
<p>o. <b>User:</b> any Person and/or his/her/its Representatives visiting, accessing, using, and/or relying on the Site, Program and/or Services, including any feature or aspect thereof, whether as a Student, an Educational Institution, a Healthcare Provider, a Representative of a Student, Educational Institution or Healthcare Provider, and/or any other Person visiting, accessing, using and/or relying on the Site, Program and/or Services.</p>
    <p><b>2. Modification of the Agreement.</b></p>
    <p>Med+Pass hereby reserves the right to add, amend, modify and/or remove Terms at any time, in its sole discretion, without prior notice to the User; provided, however, that no Med+Pass Representative may or is authorized to make any oral modification, extension or addition to this Agreement. Any addition, amendment, modification and/or revision of Terms by Med+Pass shall be effective immediately, upon being posted to the Site, and shall apply to all access and use of the Site, Programs and/or Services thereafter. User’s use and/or continued use of the Site, Program and/or Services after the posting of a revised Agreement shall be deemed User’s acceptance of, assent to and intent to be bound by the revised Agreement. User hereby acknowledges, agrees and represents that User shall read this Agreement each time User accesses this Site so that User is aware of the Terms associated with access and use of the Site, Program and/or Services.</p>
    <p><b>2. License to the User.</b></p>
    <p>The Program is licensed, not sold, to User. Subject to the Terms and User’s strict compliance with such Terms, Med+Pass grants the following User-specific license:</p>
    <p>a. <b>License to Educational Institution.</b> Med+Pass grants an Educational Institution a limited, non-exclusive, non-transferrable, non-sublicensable, revocable license to access and use the Program solely:</p>
        <p>
        <p>- to distribute Students information about the Program to enable Students to establish an Account and make permissible use of the Program, as set forth in this Agreement;</p>
        <p>- to post and/or update the Educational Institution’s immunization requirements, if displayed through the Program;</p>
        <p>- to review compliance by Students with the Educational Institution’s immunization requirements;</p>
        <p>- to notify, or cause to be notified, Students about the Educational Institution’s immunization requirements, including a Student’s compliance or non-compliance with such immunization requirements;</p>
        <p>- to receive notifications regarding the Program and/or any aspect thereof;</p>
        <p>- to seek and/or receive technical support and other Services from Med+Pass; and</p>
        <p>- to use the Program in any other manner expressly agreed, in writing, by the Educational Institution and Med+Pass.</p>
        <p><b>c. License to the Healthcare Provider.</b> Med+Pass grants a Healthcare Provider a limited, non-exclusive, non-transferrable, non-sublicensable, revocable license to access and use the Program solely:</p>
        <p>- to review Educational Institution immunization requirements, if displayed through the Program;</p>
        <p>- to submit, or cause to be submitted, Student immunization records through the Program;</p>
        <p>- to receive notifications regarding an Educational Institution’s immunization requirements, including a Student’s compliance or non-compliance with such immunization requirements;</p>
        <p>- to receive notifications regarding the Program and/or any aspect thereof;</p>
        <p>- to seek and/or receive technical support and other Services from Med+Pass; and</p>
        <p>- to use the Program in any other manner expressly agreed, in writing, by the Healthcare Provider and Med+Pass.</p>
        <p><b>d. Limited Grant and No Implied Licenses.</b> Except for the rights expressly granted in subparagraphs 3.a. through c. above, this Agreement does not grant User or any other Person (including User’s Representatives) any right, title, or interest by implication, estoppel, or otherwise, and all rights not expressly granted by Med+Pass in this Agreement are retained by Med+Pass.</p>
        <p><b>e. Notwithstanding the grant of a User-specific license in subparagraphs 3.a. through c. above</b>, that User-specific license does not allow User to use the Program on any device that User does not own or control, and User may not distribute or make the Program available over a network where it could be used by multiple devices at the same time. User may not rent, lease, loan, sell, redistribute, transfer or sublicense the Program, and User acknowledges that any such rent, lease, loan, sell, redistribution, transfer or sublicense of the Software is void. User may not adapt, copy, decompile, decrypt, reverse engineer, disassemble, attempt to derive the source code of, modify, or create derivative works of the Program or any part thereof such as pictures, music, barcodes, video, data, hyperlinks, displays and other content associated with the Program (except as and only to the extent any foregoing restriction is prohibited by applicable law or to the extent as may be permitted by the licensing terms governing use of any open sourced components included with the Program). Any attempt to take actions described in this subparagraph 3.e. shall be a violation of Med+Pass’s rights. User acknowledges that the Program contains trade secrets of Med+Pass or its suppliers, vendors, affiliates and/or licensors, including, but not limited to, the internal design and structure of the Program and associated interface information; and, therefore, User may not disclose, provide or otherwise make available trade secrets concerning, relating to or contained within the Program to any Person without the prior written consent of Med+Pass. If the above restrictions are breached by User, then User may be subject to prosecution and damages. The Terms of this Agreement will govern any updates or upgrades of the Program, unless such updates or upgrades are accompanied by a separate license in which case the terms of that license will govern.</p>
        <p><b>4. Termination of License.</b></p>
        <p>The license granted by this Agreement is effective until the date when the applicable TSA expires and/or is otherwise terminated by Med+Pass or the Educational Institution, in accordance with the Terms of this Agreement and/or the TSA. A license granted to Students and/or Healthcare Providers is derivative of the license granted to the Educational Institution with which the Student is affiliated, and therefore, the Student’s and/or Healthcare Provider’s license terminates at the same time as the termination of the Educational Institution’s license, or at such time when the Student is no longer enrolled at the Educational Institution, whichever first occurs. User hereby acknowledges and agrees that User’s rights and license granted under this Agreement terminate automatically if User fails to comply with any of the Terms. Upon termination of the license, User hereby acknowledges and agrees that User shall immediately cease any and all use of the Program, including any derivative applications or propriety knowledge related thereto, and destroy all copies thereof, full or partial, and shall cease access to the Site and/or use of any Account. USER HEREBY ACKNOWLEDGES, AGREES AND REPRESENTS THAT ANY CONSENT GIVEN BY USER DURING THE TERM OF A VALID LICENSE SHALL SURVIVE TERMINATION OF ANY LICENSE, THE AGREEMENT, AND/OR AND THE TSA.</p>
        <p><b>5. Consent and/or Authorization by Student.</b></p>
        <p>By accessing and using the Site, Program and/or Services, Student or his/her duly authorized Representative hereby consents to and authorizes Med+Pass and its Representatives to use, disclose and release protected health information and protected information from Student’s education record to another Person. Specifically, Student and/or his/her duly authorized Representative consents to and authorizes the use, disclosure and release of Student’s complete health record (including records relating to immunizations; past, present and future physical and mental health or condition; the provision of health care to Student; past, present and future payment for the provision of health care to Student). Similarly, Student and/or his/her duly authorized Representative consents to and authorizes the use, disclosure and release of protected information from Student’s education record (including educational information, personally identifiable information and directory information). Student’s complete health record (including records relating to immunizations, medical treatments and diagnosis and mental health care) and education records (including educational information, personally identifiable information and directory information) may be used by Med+Pass and its Representatives for use with the Program and/or Services, for informational purposes, for reporting purposes (including reporting compliance or non-compliance with an Educational Institution’s immunization requirements) and any other purposes authorized by Student. This consent and authorization is effective for and during all past, present and future periods and shall remain in full force and effect until the termination of this Agreement or January 1, 2020, whichever first occurs. Student and/or his/her duly authorized Representative acknowledges that he/she has the right to revoke this authorization, in writing, at any time, but that a revocation is not effective to the extent that any Person has already acted in reliance on a prior authorization. Student and/or his/her duly authorized Representative hereby acknowledges that he/she understands that information used, disclosed and/or released pursuant to this authorization may be disclosed by the recipient and may no longer be protected by applicable law. Student’s and/or his/her duly authorized Representative’s completion of the name portion of the Account set-up and/or registration constitutes an electronic signature for Student’s consent and authorization under this paragraph 5 of the Agreement.</p>
        <p><b> 6. Modification of the Program.</b></p>
        <p>Med+Pass hereby reserves the right to permanently and/or temporarily change, disable, discontinue, modify and/or suspend the Program and/or Services, including, but not limited to, the accessibility, appearance, features, functions and use of the Program, at any time, without prior notice to User. Med+Pass hereby further reserves the right to update, upgrade and/or to release subsequent versions of the Program, without prior notice to the User, and to require the User to update or upgrade its version of the Program and/or use the most recent version of the Program, in order to obtain access and use of the Program. Med+Pass may also impose limits on the use of or access to certain Services, in any case and without notice or liability.</p>
        <p>a. Notice to Educational Institution of Material Alterations. If a modification of the Program materially impairs Med+Pass’s ability to perform under a TSA, Med+Pass will provide notice to the Educational Institution prior to implementing such modification.</p>
        <p>b. Not Liable for Modifications. In no event shall Med+Pass be liable for any permanent and/or temporary change, disablement, discontinuance, modification, suspension, update and/or upgrade of the Program and/or Services.</p>
        <p>c. User Responsible for Obtaining Updated Version. Notice of the availability of a modified, updated and/or upgraded version of the Program serves as notice to all Users that use of the updated version of the Program is necessary to obtain full functionality. All changes are effective immediately, upon being posted or implemented by Med+Pass, and apply to all access and use of the Program thereafter.</p>
        <p>d. License Exchange. Any modification, update and/or upgrade from an earlier version of the Program is provided on a license-exchange basis, whereby User agrees by downloading, installing, accessing and/or using the modified, updated and/or upgraded version of the Program to voluntarily terminate any earlier license and discontinue use of the earlier version of the Program.</p>
        <p><b>7. Account Access and Security.</b></p>
        <p>User hereby acknowledges, agrees and represents that User shall be responsible for taking all actions and/or making all arrangements necessary to have access to the Program. Additionally, to obtain Account access and for security purposes, User hereby acknowledges and agrees to the following:</p>
        <p>a. User Registration. To access the Program or some of the resources it offers, User may be required to provide information, including personal and/or private information. It is an express condition of User’s access to and use of the Program that all information provided by User is correct, current and complete. User hereby acknowledges and agrees that all information provided to register through the Site or Application, including, but not limited to, through the use of any interactive features on the Site or Application, is governed by Med+Pass’s Privacy Policy (located at https://www.medpasshealth.com/Policies/Privacy), and User hereby consents to all actions Med+Pass takes with respect to the User’s information, so long as Med+Pass’s actions are consistent with any applicable law.</p>
        <p>b. Confidentiality of Account Information. If the User chooses, or is provided with, a user name, password or any other piece of information as part of Med+Pass’s security procedures, the User must treat such information as confidential, and must not disclose it to any other Person. User also hereby acknowledges and agrees that User’s Account is personal to such User and that User shall not to provide any other Person with access to the Program or portions of it using User’s user name, password or other security information. User hereby agrees to notify Med+Pass immediately of any unauthorized access to or use of User’s user name, password and other security information or any other breach of security. User hereby agrees to ensure that User exits from the Account at the end of each session. User should take particular caution when accessing the Account from a public or shared computer so that another Person is unable to view or record User’s password and/or personal, private information.</p>
        <p>c. Authority to Deactivate Account. Med+Pass hereby retains the right to disable any User Account (including any user name, password or other identifier), whether chosen by User or provided by Med+Pass, at any time in Med+Pass’s sole and exclusive discretion for any or no reason, including if, in Med+Pass’s opinion, User has violated any Term or this Agreement.</p>
        <p>d. Educational Institution’s Responsibilities. Notwithstanding anything in this Agreement, the Educational Institution is and shall be responsible for: (i) facilitating Student access to the Program; (ii) ensuring that all Persons who use the Program (including Students and Healthcare providers) are aware of the Terms; and (iii) obtaining any and all consent or authorization necessary from Users (including Students and Healthcare Providers) for their access and use of the Program and for Med+Pass to accomplish the purposes of the TSA and/or this Agreement.</p>
        <p><b>8. Lawful Use.</b></p>
        <p>User acknowledges, agrees and represents that User shall not use or otherwise export or re-export the Program, or any information collected and/or made accessible through the Program, except as authorized by United States law and the laws of the jurisdiction in which the Program was obtained and/or used. In particular, but without limitation, the Program, including any information collected and/or made accessible through the Program, may not be exported or re-exported (a) into any U.S. embargoed countries or a foreign national of such countries or (b) to anyone on the U.S. Treasury Department’s list of Specially Designated Nationals or the U.S. Department of Commerce Denied Person’s List or Entity List. By using the Program, User represents and warrants that User is not located in any such country, a foreign national of any such country (unless the User is legally present in the United States and is a Student or Healthcare Provider, as defined above), or on any such list. User also hereby acknowledges and agrees that User will not use the Program for any purposes prohibited by United States law, including, but not limited to, the development, design, manufacture or production of nuclear, missiles, or chemical or biological weapons.</p>
        <p><b>9. Prohibited Uses.</b></p>
        <p>In addition to any and all other limitations, prohibitions and/or restrictions in the Terms of this Agreement, User hereby acknowledges, agrees and represents that:</p>
        <p>a. User shall not use the Program in a manner that offers or promotes services that may be damaging to, disparaging of or otherwise detrimental to Med+Pass or its licensors, licensees, affiliates and/or partners;</p>
<p>b. User shall not transfer, display or otherwise provide content or functionality from Med+Pass to anyone who is not a Student, Educational Institution or Healthcare Provider, without the express written consent of Med+Pass;</p>
<p>c. User shall not modify or customize any aspect of the Program, without the express written consent of Med+Pass;</p>
<p>d. User shall not use the Program in a manner that interferes with, disrupts, damages and/or accesses in an unauthorized manner the servers, networks and/or other properties and services of any third party;</p>
<p>e. User shall keep any and all information uploaded and/or submitted, reviewed, verified or otherwise accessed through the Program strictly confidential, and shall not disseminate any such information in any unauthorized manner, through any unauthorized channels, and/or in any way that does not comport with applicable law;</p>
<p>f. User shall be solely responsible for transmission of any data, content, and/or resources User improperly creates, transmits and/or displays through the Program, and for the consequences of Users actions by doing so;</p>
<p>g. User shall protect the privacy and other legal rights of any other User and/or Person, including, but not limited to, names, user names, passwords, log-in information, personal information, education or medical records and/or other confidential, proprietary or otherwise sensitive information about Persons;</p>
<p>h. User shall not remove, obscure and/or alter any proprietary rights notices (including patent, copyright and trademark notices) that may be affixed to and/or contained with or within the Program;</p>
<p>i. User shall not, and shall not permit any Person, directly or indirectly, to take any actions that may cause or result in the fragmentation of the Program and/or Med+Pass’s products and services or otherwise negatively affect MedPass, including, but not limited to, distributing, participating in the creation of and/or promotion in any way of a computer program, software and/or software development kit derived in any way from the Program;</p>
<p>j. User shall not use the Program for the purpose of exploiting, harming or attempting to exploit or harm minors in any way by exposing them to inappropriate content, by impermissibly asking for personally identifiable information, or otherwise;</p>
<p>k. User shall not use the Program to impersonate or attempt to impersonate Med+Pass, a Med+Pass Representative, another User or any other Person;</p>
<p>l. User shall not use the Program in any manner that could disable, overburden, damage, or impair the Site or interfere with any other User’s use of the Site;</p>
<p>m. User shall not use any robot, spider or other automatic or manual device, process or means to access the Program for any purpose, including monitoring or copying any of the material on the Site;</p>
<p>n. User shall not introduce any viruses, Trojan horses, worms, logic bombs or other material which is malicious or technologically harmful;</p>
<p>o. User shall not attempt to gain unauthorized access to, interfere with, damage or disrupt any parts of the Program, the server on which the Program is stored, or any server, computer or database connected to the Program; and</p>
<p>p. User shall not attempt to interfere with the proper working of the Program</p></p>
    <p><b>10. Proprietary Rights.</b></p>
    <p>Med+Pass shall own and retain all right, title and interest, including, but not limited to all intellectual property rights, in and to (i) the Program and any and all elements, parts, portions and components thereof, including content, technology, software code (source and object code), APIs, user interfaces and any derivative works and/or compilations thereof; (ii) Med+Pass’s copyrights, patents, trademarks, trade secrets and/or other proprietary documents and information; and (iii) any suggestions or feedback provided by User (including suggestions, comments, improvements, ideas, etc.) concerning or relating to Med+Pass, the Site, Program and/or Services, any customized aspects of the Program that Med+Pass may have developed or be developing, any plug-ins, any applications that Med-Pass may have developed or be developing and/or any proprietary knowledge related thereto whether acquired through use of the Program or otherwise.</p>
    <p><b>11. Med+Pass Program Development.</b></p>
    <p>If a User requests customization of the Program and/or development-related Services, and Med+Pass agrees to provide a customized Program and/or development-related Services, User hereby acknowledges, agrees and represents that Med+Pass shall own and retain all right, title and interest in and to the customized Program (including its features, applications and content) and/or Services. User hereby acknowledges, agrees and represents that Med+Pass may market such customized Program (including its features, applications and content) and/or Services as part of Med+Pass’s standard Program and Services, and/or may incorporate such customized Program (including its features, applications and content) and/or Services into Med+Pass’s standard Program and Services.  Nothing in this Agreement may be construed as restricting and/or preventing Med+Pass from creating and fully exploiting such customized Program (including its features, applications and content) and/or Services, without any obligation to User.  If User elects to obtain a customized Program, development-related Services and/or provide Med+Pass with any suggestions or feedback concerning the Program and/or Services, User hereby assigns (and acknowledges, agrees and represents that User’s Representatives shall assign) all right, title and interest in and to such customized Program, development-related Services, suggestions and/or feedback to Med+Pass, and User hereby acknowledges and agrees that Med+Pass shall be entitled to use, implement, protect and/or exploit any such customized Program, development-related Services, suggestions and/or feedback in any manner without restriction, to the full extent permitted by applicable law, and without any obligation of attribution, accounting and/or compensation to User (or User’s Representatives).</p>
    <p><b>12. Intellectual Property Rights.</b></p>
    <p>The entire Program (including all features, applications, content, interfaces and functionality) is, and User hereby acknowledges, agrees and represents that the entire Program is, owned by the Med+Pass, and is protected by United States and international copyright, trademark, patent, trade secret and other intellectual property or proprietary rights laws.  This Agreement simply permits Students to access and use the Program for personal, non-commercial use and permits an Educational Institution and Healthcare Provide to access and use the Program for limited commercial purposes as stated above and/or in the TSA.  User hereby acknowledges, agrees and represents that User shall not misuse or misappropriate Med+Pass’s intellectual property (including, its copyrights, trademarks, patents, trade secrets and other intellectual property or proprietary rights).</p>
    <p><b>13. Consent for Collection and Use of Technical Data.</b></p>
    <p>User agrees that Med+Pass may periodically collect, process and/or store technical and related information about User, User’s device, system, application, peripherals, and/or use of the Program, including, but not limited to: internet protocol address, hardware identification, operating system, application software, peripheral hardware, number of active plug-ins and software development kits, the successful installation and launch of software, and software usage statistics (collectively, “Technical Data”). Med+Pass will use Technical Data for internal statistical and analytical purposes to facilitate support, invoicing and/or online services, the provisioning of updates, and the development of Med+Pass products and services.  Med+Pass may transfer Technical Data to other companies from time to time.  All information collected by Med+Pass is will be kept confidential, to the full extent required by applicable law, and is subject to Med+Pass’s Privacy Policy (available at https://www.medpasshealth.com/Policies/Privacy). By accessing or using the Site, Program and/or Services, User consents to all actions taken by Med+Pass with respect to User information, in compliance with the Privacy Policy and to the extent permitted by applicable law.</p>
    <p><b>14. Reliance on Information.</b></p>
    <p>The information contained or presented on the Site and/or through the Program is made available solely for general information purposes and/or provided by Persons such as Educational Institutions or Healthcare Providers.  Med+Pass does not warrant the accuracy, completeness or usefulness of such information.  Any reliance by User on such information is strictly at User’s own risk.  Med+Pass disclaims any liability or responsibility for, and User hereby acknowledges, agrees and represents that Med+Pass and its Representatives shall not be liable or responsible for, any information provided, transmitted, communicated, received and/or relied upon by User from Med+Pass or its Representatives.</p>
    <p><b>15. Geographic Restrictions.</b></p>
    <p>The owner of the Site, Program and/or Services is based in the state of Tennessee in the United States.  Med+Pass provides the Site, Program and/or Services for use only by Persons located in the United States.  Med+Pass makes no claims that the Site, Program, Services or any content is accessible or appropriate outside of the United States.  Access to and use of the Site, Program and/or Services may not be legal by certain Persons or in certain countries.  If User accesses or uses the Site, Program and/or Services from outside the United States, User does so on User’s own initiative and shall be responsible for compliance with applicable law.</p>
    <p><b>16. Disclaimer of Warranties</b></p>
    <p>USER HEREBY EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES AND AGREES THAT USE OF THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES IS AT USER’S SOLE RISK AND THAT THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO SATISFACTORY QUALITY, PERFORMANCE, ACCURACY, AND EFFORT IS WITH USER. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR ANY SERVICES PERFORMED OR PROVIDED BY MED+PASS’S SITE AND/OR PROGRAM ARE PROVIDED “AS IS” AND “AS AVAILABLE”, WITH ALL FAULTS AND WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, AND MED+PASS HEREBY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS WITH RESPECT TO THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR ANY SERVICES, EITHER EXPRESS, IMPLIED OR STATUTORY, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND/OR CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, OF SATISFACTORY QUALITY, OF FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OF ACCURACY, OF QUIET ENJOYMENT, OF NON-INFRINGEMENT OF THIRD-PARTY RIGHTS, OR ARISING FROM A COURSE OF DEALING, LAW, USAGE OR TRADE PRACTICE. MED+PASS DOES NOT WARRANT AGAINST INTERFERENCE WITH USER’S ENJOYMENT OF THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES; THAT THE FUNCTIONS CONTAINED IN, OR SERVICES PERFORMED OR PROVIDED BY, THE SITE AND/OR PROGRAM WILL MEET USER’S REQUIREMENTS; THAT THE OPERATION OF THE SITE AND/OR PROGRAM WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE; OR THAT DEFECTS IN THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES WILL BE CORRECTED.  NO ORAL OR WRITTEN INFORMATION OR ADVICE GIVEN BY MED+PASS OR ITS REPRESENTATIVES SHALL CREATE A WARRANTY.  SHOULD THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES PROVE DEFECTIVE, USER ASSUMES THE ENTIRE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.</p>
    <p>NEITHER MED+PASS NOR ITS REPRESENTATIVES SHALL BE LIABLE FOR ANY LOSS OR DAMAGE CAUSED BY A DISTRIBUTED DENIAL-OF-SERVICE ATTACK, VIRUSES OR OTHER TECHNOLOGICALLY HARMFUL MATERIAL THAT MAY INFECT USER’S COMPUTER EQUIPMENT, COMPUTER PROGRAMS, DATA OR OTHER PROPRIETARY MATERIAL DUE TO USER’S USE OF THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR ANY SERVICES OR ITEMS OBTAINED THROUGH THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR DUE TO USER’S DOWNLOADING OF ANY MATERIAL POSTED ON THE SITE AND/OR PROGRAM.</p>
    <p>ACCESS AND USE OF THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES MAY OCCUR ACROSS THE NETWORKS OF A NUMBER OF INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDERS AND/OR WIRELESS SERVICE PROVIDERS.  NEITHER MED+PASS NOR ITS REPRESENTATIVES OPERATE THESE NETWORKS AND HAVE NO CONTROL OVER THE OPERATIONS OF THE INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDERS AND/OR WIRELESS SERVICE PROVIDERS.  NEITHER MED+PASS NOR ITS REPRESENTATIVES WILL NOT BE LIABLE TO USER IF CIRCUMSTANCES BEYOND MED+PASS’S CONTROL INTERRUPT, PREVENT, OR OTHERWISE AFFECT THE TRANSMISSION, COMMUNICATION, POST, TRANSACTION OR OTHERWISE INTERFERE WITH THE INTEGRITY THEREOF, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, UNAVAILABILITY OF INTERNET OR WIRELESS SERVICE, COMMUNICATIONS, NETWORK DELAYS, LIMITATIONS ON WIRELESS COVERAGE, SYSTEM OUTAGES, OR INTERRUPTION OF AN INTERNET OR WIRELESS CONNECTION.  MED+PASS DISCLAIMS ANY RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY INTERNET OR WIRELESS SERVICE USED TO ACCESS THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES.</p>
    <p>USE OF THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES MAY INVOLVE THE ELECTRONIC TRANSMISSION OF PERSONAL AND/OR FINANCIAL INFORMATION ACROSS THE NETWORKS OF INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDERS AND/OR WIRELESS SERVICE PROVIDERS.  BECAUSE MED+PASS DOES NOT OPERATE OR CONTROL THE NETWORKS USED TO ACCESS THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES, MED+PASS CANNOT GUARANTEE THE PRIVACY OR SECURITY OF INTERNET OR WIRELESS DATA TRANSMISSIONS.  ADDITIONALLY, THE WIRELESS DEVICE BROWSER IS GENERALLY PRE-CONFIGURED BY USER’S WIRELESS INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER. CHECK WITH USER’S SERVICE PROVIDER FOR INFORMATION ABOUT THEIR PRIVACY AND SECURITY PRACTICES.  FOR PERSONAL OR CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION SENT TO OR FROM MED+PASS OVER THE INTERNET FROM A MOBILE DEVICE, MED+PASS REQUIRES THAT A “SECURE SESSION” BE ESTABLISHED USING TRANSPORTATION LAYER SECURITY (“TLS”).  USER’S INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER AND/OR WIRELESS SERVICE PROVIDER MAY LEVY FEES OR CHARGES FOR TRANSMISSION OR RECEIPT OF MESSAGES AND OTHER COMMUNICATIONS PERFORMED USING USER’S DEVICE OR OTHER EQUIPMENT ON THEIR NETWORK, AND USER IS SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR SUCH CHARGES.</p>
    <p><b>17. Limitation of Liability.</b></p>
    <p>TO THE EXTENT NOT PROHIBITED BY APPLICABLE LAW AND TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, USER HEREBY ACKNOWLEDGES AND AGREES THAT IN NO EVENT SHALL MED+PASS OR ITS REPRESENTATIVES BE LIABLE FOR DEATH, PERSONAL INJURY, PROPERTY DAMAGE, OR ANY DIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, EXEMPLARY OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES WHATSOEVER, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF ACTUAL OR ANTICIPATED REVENUE OR PROFIT, LOSS OF CAPTIAL, LOSS OF USE, LOSS OF GOODWILL, LOSS OF ANTICIPATED SAVINGS, LOSS OF BUSINESS, LOSS OF OPPORTUNITY, LOSS OF REPUTATION, LOSS OF OR DAMAGE TO DATA, BUSINESS INTERRUPTION OR ANY OTHER COMMERCIAL DAMAGES OR OTHER LOSSES OF ANY KIND, ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO THE LICENSE OF THE PROGRAM, THIS AGREEMENT, THE TSA, IN ANY WAY RELATED TO USER’S USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES, HOWEVER CAUSED, OR OTHERWISE, REGARDLESS OF THE THEORY OF LIABILITY (CONTRACT, TORT, STATUTORY OR OTHERWISE) AND EVEN IF MED+PASS HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.  In no event shall MED+PASS’S total liability to User for all damages (other than as may be required by applicable law in cases involving personal injury) exceed FIFTY DOLLARS ($50.00).  THE LIMITATION OF LIABILITY IN THIS PARAGRAPH 17 IS CUMULATIVE AND NOT PER INCIDENT, OCCURRENCE, DAMAGE OR INJURY (I.E., THE EXISTENCE OF TWO OR MORE CLAIMS WILL NOT ENLARGE THIS LIMIT).  ThE Limitation OF LIABILITY IN THIS PARAGRAPH 17 and the disclaimer in PARAGRAPH 16 above will apply even if the above-stated remedy fails of its essential purpose.</p>
    <p><b>18. Indemnification.</b></p>
    <p>User shall indemnify, defend and hold Med+Pass and its Representatives harmless from any action, proceeding, claim, cause of action, demand, complaint, grievance, injury, damage, relief or liability (individually and collectively, “Claim”), including reasonable attorneys’ fees, made by any Person due to, concerning, relating to or arising out of User’s access or use of the Program and/or Services, User’s negligent, wanton and/or intentional acts or omissions, User’s infringement of a third-party’s intellectual property, and User’s breach of the Terms.  User shall use best efforts to cooperate with Med+Pass in the defense of any such Claim.  Med+Pass reserves the right, at Med+Pass’s expense, to employ separate counsel and assume the exclusive defense and control of any such Claim subject to indemnification by User.</p>
    <p><b>19. Commercial Status.</b></p>
    <p>The Program is a “Commercial Item,” as that term is defined at 48 C.F.R. 2.101, consisting of “Commercial Computer Software” and “Commercial Computer Software Documentation”, as such terms are used in 48 C.F.R. 12.212 or 48 C.F.R. 227.7202, as applicable. Consistent with 48 C.F.R. 12.212 or 48 C.F.R. 227.7202-1 through 227.7202-4, as applicable, the Commercial Computer Software and Commercial Computer Software Documentation are being licensed to U.S. Government end users (a) only as Commercial Items and (b) with only those rights as are granted to all other end users pursuant to the Terms of this Agreement.  Unpublished rights are reserved under the copyright laws of the United States.</p>
    <p><b>20. Governing Law, Jurisdiction.</b></p>
    <p>User’s access and use of the Site, Program and/or Services is governed by, construed and enforced in accordance with the laws of the state of Tennessee, USA and applicable federal law without regard to conflicts of laws principles.  Any Claim concerning, relating to or arising out of this Agreement, the Terms, access or use of the Site, Program, Services and/or the relationship between Med+Pass and User shall be brought solely and exclusive in the applicable state or federal courts located in Nashville, Tennessee, USA, and the User acknowledges that no other court(s) will have jurisdiction or venue over any such claim.  User expressly consents to the personal jurisdiction and venue of the applicable state and federal courts located in Tennessee.  User’s use of the Program may also be subject to other local, state, national or international laws.</p>
    <p><b>21. Limitation on Time to File Claims.</b></p>
    <p>ANY CLAIM USER MAY HAVE CONCERNING, RELATING TO OR ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT, THE TERMS, ACCESS OR USE OF THE SITE, PROGRAM AND/OR SERVICES AND/OR THE RELATINOSHIP BETWEEN MED+PASS AND USER SHALL BE INITIATED OR COMMENCED WITHIN AND NO LATER THAN ONE (1) YEAR AFTER THE CLAIM ACCRUES, OTHERWISE, SUCH CLAIM IS PERMANENTLY BARRED.</p>
    <p><b>22. Third Party Beneficiaries.</b></p>
    <p>This Agreement is for the sole benefit of Med+Pass, User and their successors, and nothing in this Agreement, express or implied, shall give or be construed to give any Person other than Med+Pass and User any legal or equitable rights whatsoever.</p>
    <p><b>23. Severability.</b></p>
    <p>If any Term shall be deemed invalid, void or for any reason unenforceable, that Term or those Terms shall be deemed severable and shall not affect the validity and enforceability of any remaining Terms.  Failure of Med+Pass to exercise or enforce any right or provision of this Agreement shall not constitute a waiver of such right or provision in that or any other instance.</p>
    <p><b>24. Injunctive Relief.</b></p>
    <p>User hereby acknowledges, agrees and represents that Med+Pass shall have the right to obtain an injunction against any unauthorized use of the Site, Program and/or Services by User secured by a nominal bond of no more than One Hundred Dollars ($100.00), in addition to any other rights and remedies to which Med+Pass may be entitled.</p>
    <p><b>25. Headings.</b></p>
    <p>The headings in this Agreement are for convenience only and shall not affect the construction or interpretation of any Term of this Agreement.</p>
    <p><b>26. Construction.</b></p>
    <p>This Agreement shall be construed without regard to any presumption or other rule requiring construction against any party drafting or causing this Agreement to be drafted.  Whenever the context of this Agreement directs, the plural shall be read as the singular and the singular as the plural.</p>
    <p><b>27. No Assignment.</b></p>
    <p>User shall not assign or delegate any of its rights or obligations under this Agreement to any other Person without the prior written consent of Med+Pass.  Any assignment or delegation in violation of this provision shall be null and void.</p>
    <p><b>28. Entire Agreement.</b></p>
    <p>This Agreement, along with any additional understandings or agreements expressly incorporated in and/or made subject to this Agreement (including, but not limited to, the TSA), constitutes the entire understanding and agreement between Med+Pass and User with respect to the subject matter of this Agreement and supersedes all prior or contemporaneous oral or written communications with respect thereto.</p>
    <p><b>29. Authority.</b></p>
    <p>User acknowledges and represents that he/she, individually or on behalf of an employer or other Person, has full legal authority to bind himself/herself and/or his/her employer or other principal to this Agreement.  If User does not have the requisite authority or capacity, he/she may not accept this Agreement or access or use the Site, Program and/or Services.</p>
    <p><b>30. User Comments and Concerns.</b></p>
    <p>This Site is operated by MedPass Health LLC, 3127 Long Boulevard, No. 105, Nashville, Tennessee, USA 37203.  All feedback, comments, requests for technical support and other communications relating to the Site and/or Program should be directed to: hallett.ogburn@medpasshealth.com.</p>
    ]]>
</string>

</resources>